DOGUHAN YEKE

Website://doguhanyeke Github://doguhanyeke Linkedin://DoguhanYeke

305 N. University Street West Lafayette, IN 47907, USA & dyeke@purdue.edu & +1 (765) 701-9263

SUMMARY

I am a systems security researcher in the Department of Computer Science at Purdue University, working in the PurSec Lab. My research primarily focuses on mobile security, including smartphones and smartwatches; the safety and security of autonomous systems, such as UAVs; and practical deep learning applications in security.

EDUCATION

Purdue University, US

 $August\ 2021\ -\ Ongoing$

Ph.D, Computer Science

3.65/4.00

Advisors: Asst.Prof. Z. Berkay Celik and Asst.Prof. Antonio Bianchi

Middle East Technical University(METU), Turkey

June 2017 - July, 2020

M.Sc, Computer Engineering

4.00/4.00

3.24/4.00

Graduated with the top grade, Ranked 1st

Thesis: Improving Document Ranking with Query Expansion based on BERT Word Embeddings

Advisor: Prof.Dr. Nihan Kesim Cicekli

Middle East Technical University(METU), Turkey

September 2013 - June 2017

B.Sc, Computer Engineering

Graduated with Honors

Advisor: Assoc.Prof. Yusuf Sahillioglu

ACADEMIC AND RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Department of Computer Science at Purdue University, US

August 2021 - Ongoing

Research and Teaching Assistant

· CS307: Software Engineering, CS251: Data Structures and Algorithms

Department of Computer Engineering at METU, Turkey

August 2018 - July 2021

Research and Teaching Assistant

· CEng492: Computer Engineering Design, CEng489: Introduction to Computer Security, CEng350: Software Engineering, CEng331: Computer Organization

eNTERFACE at University of Mons, Belgium

June 2015 - August 2015

Undergraduate Research Assistant

· Implemented Python modules for the classification of very large number of objects and used the Neo4j Graph database to visualize the classification results.

TSK Modsimmer, Turkey

August 2015 - September 2015

Summer Internship

· Wrote a simulation of a fire forest using C++ with concurrency and also implemented an interface with QT.

· Given a point of fire, the program estimates where the fire will spread using different parameters like wind speed and tree population.

Department of Computer Engineering at METU, Turkey September 2015 - January 2015 Undergraduate Teaching Assistant

· CEng230: Introduction to C Programming

PEER-REVIEWED PUBLICATIONS

C1 **Doguhan Yeke**, Muhammad Ibrahim, Guliz Seray Tuncay, Habiba Farrukh, Abdullah Imran, Antonio Bianchi, and Z. Berkay Celik

Wears my Data? Understanding the Cross-Device Runtime Permission Model in Wearables [Paper], [Code], [Slides], [News]

Proceedings of the IEEE Security and Privacy (S&P), 2024.

TALKS

Wear OS project, Android Security and Privacy Research (ASPIRE), Google (remote), October 2022

BUGS DISCOVERED

Location Privacy, awarded \$500 bug bounty by Google.

INDUSTRIAL EXPERIENCE

Comodo, Turkey

Software Developer

June 2017 - August 2018

- · Worked as a Backend Developer: used different tech stacks like Flask, Express, Javascript, Relational Databases, REST APIs, Redis, AWS and testing, etc.
- · Worked as a Security Researcher: implemented Deep Learning models for detecting malware and integrating third-party libraries into our system.
- · Worked with static and dynamic analysis tools such as Cuckoo to detect the malware.

SAP Development Center, Turkey

June 2016 - September 2016

Student(Intern) Software Developer

· Worked in the Security team as a Golang developer in an agile team during my internship.

AWARDS AND HONORS

<u>2023:</u> Served at the **NSF ACTION GATE**, Institute for Agent-based Cyber Threat Intelligence and Operation, 2023.

2023: Student contributor of Google ASPIRE Award

2022: Student contributor of Google ASPIRE Award

2021: Interpersonal Conversation Partner at Purdue University

2019: Best Course Performance Award at METU.

<u>2019</u>: **Highest Departmental cGPA** in all graduates of Master's Degree at METU.

2013-2017: **High Honor Student** in multiple semesters of Bachelor's Degree at METU.

<u>2011-2012</u>: Ranked 5th in Turkey in **Mathematics Olympiads** in High School conducted by the Scientific and Technological Research Council of Turkey (TUBITAK), sponsored by OYAK.

SERVICES

External reviewer at ACM WiSec 2024.

PROJECTS

Industrial Control System Modeling with SCEPTRE Framework May 2022 - October 2022 Sandia National Laboratories

- · Collaborated with Sandia Labs while studying at Purdue University in the summer of 2022.
- · Deployed Cyber Emulation, Modeling, and Analysis Tools on the SOL4CE.

TECHNICAL STRENGTHS

FullStack: React, Redux, Node.js, Express, MongoDB, Typescript, Mongoose, AWS Services, Inmemory database.

Languages: Python, C++, C, Javascript, Java, Scala, R, Assembly, Haskell, Verilog.

Tools: Tensorflow, Keras, PyTorch, AWS, RabbitMQ, Jupyter Notebook etc. Toefl Score: 100 Reading: 26, Listening: 26, Speaking: 25, Writing: 23 GRE Score: Quantitative: 167, Verbal: 141, Analytical Writing: 3,5

COURSES TAKEN

Undergraduate Courses: Object Oriented Programming, Cloud Computing, Machine Learning Graduate Courses: Information Security, IoT Security, Distributed Systems, Computer Networks, Algorithms, Big Data Analytics, Advanced Deep Learning, Statistical Data Analysis, Information Retrieval, Computational Geometry, Algorithmic Trading